Streib, Victor; Papers apap330
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Victor L. Streib Papers
1908-2012, Undated
1978-2007
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap330
22.8 cubic ft.
The Victor Streib Papers contain research materials and legal case files on the death penalty in the United States with a focus on how it has been applied to women and juveniles.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in the Victor L. Streib Papers were donated by Victor L. Streib in 2012.
Biographical History
Victor L. Streib was born in 1941 in Marion, Indiana. He received his undergraduate degree in Industrial Engineering from Auburn University in 1966 and then served in the Air Force. He studied law at Indiana University and received his J.D. in 1970. That same year, he joined the Indiana Bar Association, and later the U.S. Supreme Court Bar Association in 1987. He began his teaching career in 1971 at Indiana University's Department of Forensic Studies (now Criminal Justice.) He taught as a law professor at the New England School of Law, the Cleveland-Marshall College of Law, and in 1996 became Dean of the Claude W. Pettit College of Law at Ohio Northern University, retiring from that position in 2012.
In the course of his academic career, Streib authored over 300 articles, papers, books and chapters. His research on juveniles and women who were sentenced to death has been cited dozens of times in United States Supreme Court cases. One of Streib's books, The Fairer Death, has shed light on the biases against women in capital cases, concluding that capital punishment is arbitrarily applied and not necessarily for the most heinous crimes. In addition to writing specifically about women and juveniles in death penalty cases, he has argued that factors such as race, mental deficiency, poor legal representation, and defendants who do not conform to gender expectations have more impact on who is sentenced to death than the facts of the crime.
In addition to his scholarly work, Streib has served as counsel and co-counsel on capital cases, including notable cases he has argued in front of the United States Supreme Court. These landmark cases include his service as appellate counsel for the 1988 case Thompson v. Oklahoma, which resulted in the Court's decision to prohibit executing persons who were under sixteen at the time of their crime. He also served as counsel for Roper v. Simmons, the 2005 Supreme Court ruling that decided executing persons younger than age eighteen at the time of their crime is a violation of the Eighth and Fourteenth Amendments, and therefore unconstitutional.
As a conscientious objector, Streib has worked to change the culture of violence in America, especially the way that the death penalty's focus has been on vengeance rather than rehabilitation. His writing is objective and measured, and his research on the inconsistencies of capital punishment has protected an unknown number of juveniles from being sentenced to death since 2005. Much of Streibs scholarship has been aided by Watt Espys collection of death penalty files, and Streib has stated that his work is credited to "standing on the shoulders of Watt Espy." Some of Streibs papers were co-authored with his wife, Dr. Lynn Sametz. They have now retired to North Carolina, where they live with their pets, Charles Duke of Ada (a dog), Pywacket (a cat), Atticus (a cat), and Scout (a dog).
Scope and Contents
The Victor Streib Papers contain research materials on the death penalty in the United States with a focus on how it has been applied to women and juveniles.
The collection contains case files, papers, journal articles and other written materials about juveniles and women who were sentenced to death. There are a number of topical articles about historic and modern death penalty cases written by Victor Streib and others. Some of these articles are scholarly in nature, and some were written for general audiences. The general interest materials include articles in magazines about particular death penalty cases that Streib was either working on or interested in, as well as publications that exist to chronicle the state of death penalty cases in the United States.
The bulk of the collection consists of materials from Streib's case work from the mid-1980s to the mid-2000s, when he was working as counsel to a handful of death penalty cases, and researching the history of how that punishment has been applied in the United States.
The case files in his research collection are part of an attempt, in conjunction with the Watt Espy Papers, to document all of the cases of state-sponsored executions of women and juveniles in the United States. Some of the files are cross-referenced with Espy's notecards. The collection includes case files from Streib's most notable cases as a lawyer, including Paula Cooper of Indiana, Wayne Thompson of Oklahoma, and Christopher Simmons of Missouri, which led to a groundbreaking Supreme Court decision to abolish the death penalty for juveniles.
Arrangement of the Collection
The archivist retained Series 1's original order as a reference collection. Each sub-series is filed alphabetically by state, (including Washington, D.C., federal, and Puerto Rico) and then alphabetically by the last name of the subject within the state. In the case of slaves or servants with only a first name, those files are alphabetical by first name, although they are sometimes listed on the index cards within the file under the last name of the slave owner. In the cases where the name is not known, the files are alphabetized by the index heading on the card.
Series 2 is organized alphabetically by title.
Series 1 - Case Files, 1947-2012, Undated
Subseries 1.1: Executed Women, United States, 1947-2008, Undated
Subseries 1.2: Sentenced Women, United States, 1983-2012, Undated
Subseries 1.3: Executed Juveniles, United States, 1982-2007, Undated
Subseries 1.4: Sentenced Juveniles, United States, 1978-2007, Undated
Subseries 1.5: Juveniles not sentenced to death, 2007, Undated
Series 2 - Reference Materials, 1908-2012, Undated
Related Materials
Archivists transferred the following monographs to the book division of Special Collections:
Victor L. Streib, The Fairer Death: Executing Women in Ohio
Victor L. Streib, Juvenile Justice in America
Beverly Lowry, Crossed Over: A Murder, A Memoir
The catalogue records for the monographs are included in the University Library Catalog.
Death Penalty; United States. Supreme Court.; Capital Punishment United States; Children Legal Status, Laws, etc.; Juvenile Corrections; Female Offenders Case Studies; Women Death Row Inmates United States Case Studies; Executions -- 1608-2004; Slaves--AmericaHistory; Capital punishment--Moral and ethical aspects; Books; Correspondence; Criminal court records; Legal documents; Magazines--Crime; Newsletters; Newspaper clippings; Pamphlets; Papers; Photographs; Streib, Victor L.
- Case Files, 1947-2012, Undated; 1; 19 cubic ft.
  Arrangement:
  Alphabetical by state, and then alphabetical by the last name of the subject within the state.
  Contents:
  This series contains a file for every execution or sentence of death given to a woman or a juvenile that was known to Victor L. Streib. Some of the case study files are simply photocopies of Watt Espy's research cards, especially in cases where Espy's research is the sum total information available that particular execution. Many of these cards are from before 1976, when the death penalty was re-instated in America. Due to improved record-keeping in the modern era, case files from recent years, especially ones that Streib advised in some capacity, may contain significantly more information than others. Information pertinent to these cases vary greatly by individual depending on the state, the era, as well as media coverage of the case. The research collection is up-to-date as of 2012, so any executions, pardons, or reversals that went forward since that date will remain in the series they were in at the time these papers were acquired by the archives.
  - Executed Women, United States, 1947-2008, Undated; 1.1; 4 cubic ft.
    - Alabama: General, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 1)
    - Alabama: Biddy, executed 1842, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 2)
    - Alabama: Earle Dennison, executed 1958-09-04, 1985; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 3)
    - Alabama: Eliza, executed 1864, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 4)
    - Alabama: Fanny, executed 1836, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 5)
    - Alabama: Silena Gilmore, executed 1930-01-24, 1985; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 6)
    - Alabama: June, executed 1860, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 7)
    - Alabama: Lizzie, executed 1861, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 8)
    - Alabama: Linda Lyon, executed 2002-05-10, 1992; 1996; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 9)
    - Alabama: Martha, executed 1855, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 10)
    - Alabama: Rhonda Belle Martin, executed 1957-10-11, 1985; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 11)
    - Alabama: Mary, executed 1842, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 12)
    - Alabama: Pauline McCoy, executed 1888-10-12, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 13)
    - Alabama: Nancy, executed 1844-03, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 14)
    - Alabama: Nancy, executed 1859, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 15)
    - Alabama: Patsy, executed 1825-06-10, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 16)
    - Alabama: Rachel, 1827-05-25, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 17)
    - Alabama: Pherebe, executed 1849-12-11, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 18)
    - Alabama: Holly, executed 1835-01, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 19)
    - Arizona: General, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 20)
    - Arizona: Eva Dugan, executed 1930-02-21, 1985; 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 21)
    - Arizona: Dolores Moore, executed 1865, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 22)
    - Arkansas: General, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 23)
    - Arkansas: Lavinia Burnett, executed 1887-02-28, 1956; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 24)
    - Arkansas: Calvert's Slave, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 25)
    - Arkansas: Davis' Slave, 1853, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 26)
    - Arkansas: Mrs. Moses Dean, executed 1868-11, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 27)
    - Arkansas: Mary Hillhouse, executed 1832-01, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 28)
    - Arkansas: Christina Riggs, executed 2000-05-02, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 29)
    - California: General, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 30)
    - California: Elizabeth Ann Duncan, executed 1962-08-08, 2001; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 31)
    - California: Barbara Graham, executed 1955-06-03, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 32)
    - California: Kate McShane, executed 1890-07, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 33)
    - California: Louise Peele, executed 1947-04-11, 1986; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 34)
    - California: Eithel Spinelli, executed 1941-11-21, 1985; 2001; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 35)
    - California: Eithel Spinelli, executed 1941-11-21, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
    - Connecticut: general, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 36)
    - Connecticut: Hannah, executed 1731-09-15, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 37)
    - Connecticut: Mary Barnes, executed 1662-03, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 38)
    - Connecticut: Goodwife Bassett, executed 1651, 2001; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 39)
    - Connecticut: Sarah Bramble, executed 1753-11-21, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 40)
    - Connecticut: Roanna Carrington, executed 1653-03-19, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 41)
    - Connecticut: Catherine Garrett, executed 1738-05-03, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 42)
    - Connecticut: Rebecca Greensmith, executed 1662-01, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 43)
    - Connecticut: Mary Johnson, executed 1648-12, 1987; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 44)
    - Connecticut: Kate, executed 1743-11, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 45)
    - Connecticut: Goodwife Knapp, executed 1653, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 46)
    - Connecticut: Thirza Mansfield, executed 1825-07, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 47)
    - Connecticut: Hannah Ocuish, executed 1786-12-20, 1986; 1996; 2004; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 48)
    - Connecticut: Elizabeth Shaw, executed 1745-12-18, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 49)
    - Connecticut: Abigail Thompson, executed 1708-05, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 50)
    - Connecticut: Waisoiusk Squaw, executed 1711-05-15, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 51)
    - Delaware: general, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 52)
    - Delaware: Catharine Bevan, executed 1731-06-10, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 53)
    - Delaware: Margaret Borden, executed 1751, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 54)
    - Delaware: Sarah Jane Bradley, executed 1869-12-14, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 55)
    - Delaware: May Carey, executed 1935-06-07, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 56)
    - Delaware: Alice Cunningham, executed 1752-02-08, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 57)
    - Delaware: Eleanor Evans, executed 1761-05-11, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 58)
    - Delaware: Elizabeth Garrison, executed 1722, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 59)
    - Delaware: Sarah Kirk, executed 1787, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 60)
    - Delaware: Eleanor Moore, executed 1722-05-09, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 61)
    - Delaware: Judith Roe, executed 1688-03-15, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 62)
    - Delaware: Margaret Sexton, executed 1757-06, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 63)
    - Federal: general, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 64)
    - Federal: Bonnie Brown Heady, executed 1953-12-18, 1985; 1987; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 65)
    - Federal: Bonnie Brown Heady, executed 1953-12-18, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
    - Federal: Ethel Rosenberg, executed 1953-06-19, 1997; 2001; 2008; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 66)
    - Federal: Mary Surratt, executed 1865-07-07, 1994; 2001; 2002; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 67)
    - Florida: general, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 68)
    - Florida: Judi Buenoano, executed 1998-03-30, 1987; 1990; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 69)
    - Florida: Celia, executed 1848-09-22, 1989; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 70)
    - Florida: Jane McCormick, executed 1835, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 71)
    - Florida: Aileen Wuornos, executed 2002-10-09, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 72)
    - Florida: Aileen Wuornos, executed 2002-10-09, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 73)
    - Foreign: general, 1993; 1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 74)
    - Georgia: general, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 75)
    - Georgia: Lena Baker, executed 1945-03-05, 1999; 2005; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 76)
    - Georgia: Polly Barclay, executed 1806-05-30, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 77)
    - Georgia: Bella, executed 1837, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 78)
    - Georgia: Black Women, executed 1858, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 79)
    - Georgia: Malinda, executed 1851-10-24, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 80)
    - Georgia: Cind, executed 1830-06-06, 1981; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 81)
    - Georgia: Amanda Cody, executed 1895-11-22, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 82)
    - Georgia: Susan Ebehart, executed 1873-05-02, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 83)
    - Georgia: Emaline, executed 1835-05-10, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 84)
    - Georgia: Florence English, executed 1895-11-22, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 85)
    - Georgia: Finney, executed 1864 or 1865, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 86)
    - Georgia: Gross' slave, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 87)
    - Georgia: Margaret Harris, executed 1883-10-19, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 88)
    - Georgia: Ann Hunt, executed 1874-05-01, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 89)
    - Georgia: Jenny, executed 1829-12-04, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 90)
    - Georgia: Mills' Slave, 1700's, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 91)
    - Georgia: Ella Moore, executed 1882-10-20, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 92)
    - Georgia: Amy, executed 1835, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 93)
    - Georgia: Katy Murren, executed 1836, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 94)
    - Georgia: Mrs. William Nobles, executed 1895, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 95)
    - Georgia: Sophie, executed 1845-05-30, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 96)
    - Georgia: Olge Thorpe slave, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 97)
    - Georgia: Ellen Osgood, executed 1878-12-19, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 98)
    - Georgia: Reynolds' Slave 1820 or 1821, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 99)
    - Georgia: Alice Riley, executed 1735-01-19, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 100)
    - Georgia: Margaret Seaborn, executed 1817-10, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 101)
    - Georgia: Slave, unconfirmed, 1838, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 102)
    - Georgia: Bella Warren, executed 1835-12-22, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 103)
    - Georgia: Sophie White, executed 1833-04-26, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 104)
    - Georgia: Sarah Williams, executed 1859-05-27, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 105)
    - Illinois: Marie Porter, executed 1938-06-28, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 106)
    - Illinois: Marie Porter, executed 1938-06-28, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
    - Illinois: Elizabeth Reed, executed 1845-05-23, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 107)
    - Indiana: Opal Juanita collins, executed 1956, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 108)
    - Kansas: General, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 109)
    - Kentucky: Ellen Alexander, executed 1842, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 110)
    - Kentucky: Amy, executed 1844-11-30, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 111)
    - Kentucky: Mary Caldwell, executed 1830-09-04, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 112)
    - Kentucky: Cassilly, executed 1849, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 113)
    - Kentucky: Cassy, executed 1833-10-02, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 114)
    - Kentucky: Nance Chapman, executed 1809-08-04, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 115)
    - Kentucky: Caroline Dement, executed 1863-08-17, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 116)
    - Kentucky: Sarah, executed 1837-06-24, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 117)
    - Kentucky: Eliza, executed 1867-08-15, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 118)
    - Kentucky: Funny Field, executed 1799-08-03, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 119)
    - Kentucky: Frances, executed 1860-09-07, Undated (Box 1 (1-Case Files), Folder 120)
    - Kentucky: Ellenor Gillespie, executed 1817-07-26, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 1)
    - Kentucky: Mary Jane Gordon, executed 1849-02-24, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 2)
    - Kentucky: Hamilton's slave, executed 1846, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 3)
    - Kentucky: Harriet, executed 1831, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 4)
    - Kentucky: Hannah Hazelwood, executed 1834-04-30, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 5)
    - Kentucky: Isabelle Hildreth, executed 1814-08-08, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 6)
    - Kentucky: Sally Kirkland, executed 1849-04-27, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 7)
    - Kentucky: Catherine London, executed 1798-05-10, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 8)
    - Kentucky: Lucy, executed 1848-05, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 9)
    - Kentucky: Martha, executed 1839-10-04, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 10)
    - Kentucky: Martha, executed 1855, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 11)
    - Kentucky: Minerva, executed 1856-02-09, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 12)
    - Kentucky: Nancy, executed 1808-09-30, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 13)
    - Kentucky: Catherine Pearce, executed 1832-09-04, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 14)
    - Kentucky: Phoebe, executed 1808, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 15)
    - Kentucky: Caroline Roberts executed 1836-05-17, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 16)
    - Kentucky: Rumsey, executed 1812, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 17)
    - Kentucky: Hannah Smith, executed 1844-04-11, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 18)
    - Kentucky: Jane Smith, executed 1860-12-14, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 19)
    - Kentucky: Mrs. Walleck, executed 1801, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 20)
    - Kentucky: Slave Woman, executed 1824, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 21)
    - Kentucky: Woman, 1853, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 22)
    - Louisiana: general, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 23)
    - Louisiana: Ann, e. 1862-08-08, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 24)
    - Louisiana: Margaret Barrow, executed 1858, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 25)
    - Louisiana: Betty, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 26)
    - Louisiana: Blisland's slave, executed 1842, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 27)
    - Louisiana: Carolina, executed 1862-07-25, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 28)
    - Louisiana: Chloe, executed 1863-02-20, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 29)
    - Louisiana: Cyrina, executed 1849-10-26, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 30)
    - Louisiana: Elizabeth, executed 1856-04-16, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 31)
    - Louisiana: Eliza, executed 1857-03-04, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 32)
    - Louisiana: Ellen, executed 1851-11-27, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 33)
    - Louisiana: Marie (Molly) Glass, executed 1781-07-26, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 34)
    - Louisiana: Alcee Harris, executed 1875-11-26, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 35)
    - Louisiana: Toni Jo Henry, executed 1942-11-28, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 36)
    - Louisiana: Jane, executed 1837-08, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 37)
    - Louisiana: Jeannette, executed 1851, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 38)
    - Louisiana: Matilda jones, executed 1885-07-31, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 39)
    - Louisiana: LeBlanc's slave, executed 1835, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 40)
    - Louisiana: Ada Leboeuf, executed 1929-02-01, 2000; Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 41)
    - Louisiana: Lucy, executed 1832-10, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 42)
    - Louisiana: Lucy, executed 1846-12-11, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 43)
    - Louisiana: Melvaine, executed 1855-02-26, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 44)
    - Louisiana: Modeste, executed 1860-04-03, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 45)
    - Louisiana: Julia moore, executed 1935-02-08, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 46)
    - Louisiana: Patience, executed 1860-04-24, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 47)
    - Louisiana: Pauline, executed 1846-03-28, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 48)
    - Louisiana: Randolph's Slave: executed 1838, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 49)
    - Louisiana: Rose, executed 1859, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 50)
    - Louisiana: Modeste, executed 1860-04-03, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 51)
    - Louisiana: Slave, executed 1730, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 52)
    - Louisiana: Slave, executed 1829-07-10, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 53)
    - Louisiana: Slave, 1829-09-26, Undated (Box 2 (1-Case Files), Folder 54)